漫长的一天
Long day ahead.
艾琳?
Aileen?
谢谢你 爱
Thanks  love.
更像是驴子闯进来的，玛丽
More like donkeys broken in  Mary.
妈的，我们本来什么都有可能的
Fuck's sake  like  we could have been anything.
老师 护士 美发师
Teachers  nurses  hairdressers.
理发师吗?别这么野心勃勃，莎拉
Hairdressers? Don't be so ambitious  Sarah.
你没听到她叫我们蠢货吗?实际的驴
Did you not just hear her calling us donkeys? Actual asses  like.
但真是个混蛋，希拉，姑娘
But what an arse  Sheila  girl.
我的儿子!
My son!
不!
No!
马克!
Mark!
如果我什么都不做，我就教这个小混蛋游泳
If I do nothing else  I'm teaching this little fecker how to swim.
艾琳
Erin.
耶稣基督 女孩
Jesus Christ  girl.
Yera……
Yera...
操的缘故 它们真的生活在水上
for fuck's sake. They literally live on the water
他们没有一个人学会怎么做
and none of them learn how.
你知道这是传统，艾琳
You know it's the tradition  Erin.
怎么，知道就会倒霉吗?
What  it's bad luck to know?
如果他们不会游泳，他们就不会跳下去帮助别人
If they can't swim  they won't jump in and help anyone else.
一群自私的混蛋，太关心自己的皮肤了
Pack of selfish wankers  too worried about their own skins.
怎么了，奥斯卡，亲爱的?
What's wrong  Oscar  love?
一晚上会哭三四次
Wakes up crying three  four times a night.
灾难 像 -天啊，我记得和你在一起的夜晚
-Disaster  like. -Jesus Christ  I remember nights with you.
无法睡眠
Could never sleep.
骗我说我只能让你哭
Con telling me I just had to let you cry.
我怎么能这么做呢?
How could I do that?
听到噪音
Hearing every noise.
说句公道话，你是比较容易相处的孩子
You were the easier child  to be fair.
进展得怎样?我有段时间没见到你了
How's it going? I haven't see you in a while.
事情怎么样了?
How's things?
很高兴见到你
Good to see you.
你好 丹
Hi  Dan.
布莱恩·奥哈拉?你在这里做什么?
Brian O'Hara? What the hell are you doing here?
天啊，你这么大
Jesus Christ  the size of you.
你变得越强大……到这里来
The stronger you get... Come here.
从外表上看，我们都更宽广更睿智了，丹，小子
We're all wider and wiser by the look Dan boy.
加勒比海盗 -哦，孩子，一切都好吗?
-After a while. -Well boy  how's things?
布莱恩
Brian.
基督 布莱恩……
Christ  Brian...
妈，看看你
Mom  look at you  huh.
——你的头发 你一点也没变
- Your hair. You haven't changed a bit.
这是谁?
Who's this  huh?
是我的小弟弟，对吧?
It's my baby brother  is it?
什么!不 不 不 耶稣基督
What! No  no  no. Jesus Christ.
哦，到我这儿来
Oh  come here to me.
哦
Oh.
帕迪，最近怎么样?
Well  Paddy  how's things?
你个混蛋
You son of a bitch.
——布莱恩!——艾琳!
- Brian! - Erin!
什么他妈的!你在这里做什么?
What the fuck! What are you doing here?
我该回来了，不是吗?
It's 'bout time I came back  isn't it?
——莎拉 ——布莱恩
- Sarah. - Brian.
马克·菲兹死了你才会回到我们身边，是吗?
It takes Mark Fitz dying for you to come back to us  does it?
什么?
What?
这是给他的吗?
That's who this is for?
我操，就是这样
Ah  fuck me  it is.
我很抱歉
I'm so sorry.
给我一点时间
Just give me one second.
玛丽 嗯…
Mary  um...
我很抱歉，玛丽
I'm so sorry  Mary.
-很抱歉 ——谢谢
- I'm so sorry. - Thank you.
帕迪这样多久了?
How long has Paddy been like this?
在这个阶段已经有好几年了
A good few years now at this stage.
-回来一定很奇怪 嗯
-Must be weird being back. -Hmm.
可能是一模一样的，对吧?
Probably the exact fuckin' same  though  is it?
她会停下来吗?
Does she ever stop going?
你不在的时候，一秒钟都没有
Oh  not a second all the time you were gone.
一分钟 爱
One minute  love.
爸爸，是吗?
That dad  is it?
你应该出去见见他 他就像这样
You should go out and meet him. He'd like that.
继续
Go on.
你好吗?-哦 是的 是的
-You good? -Oh yeah  yeah.
看到他们握手真奇怪
Strange seeing them shake hands.
他与众不同，不是吗?成长为自己
He's different  isn't he? Grown into himself.
你认为吗?
Do you reckon?
母亲知道
A mother knows.
你脸上的表情
The look on your face.
-别那么震惊，伙计 -什么?
-Don't be so shocked  mate. -What?
-她喂过你吗?-哦 不 还没有
- Has she fed you? - Uh  no. Not yet.
很难相信他回来了，是吧?
Hard to believe he's home  huh?
回家真好，好吧
Good to be home now  all right.
那么，你在澳大利亚
So  you're in Australia.
多久没和我们联系了?
Not been in touch with us in how long?
你突然就有了回家的念头
And you get a notion  all of a sudden  to come home.
糟糕的天气，该死的工作，却不告诉任何人?
Shit weather  fuck all work  and not tell anyone?
是的 差不多就是这么大了，是的
Yeah. That's about the size of it  yeah.
拜托，你怎么回来了?
Come on  why are you back  like?
嗯…
Uh...
水稻的牡蛎
Paddy's oysters.
基督 你又要从零开始了 你攒钱了吗?
Christ. Oh  you be starting from nothing again. Have you money saved?
牡蛎把工作 他们并不便宜
Oysters take work. They aren't cheap.
但我们还有许可证
But we still have the license for it.
我一直在还款
I kept up the payments.
Con放弃后的每一年
Every year since Con gave up on it.
以防
Just in case.
它向前倾斜 -好的
-Tilt it forward. -Okay.
-是那边吗?——是的
- Is it that way? - Yes.
-可以吗?-是的
- That all right? - Yeah.
我看到你照顾它了
I see you looked after it.
我父亲再也无法忍受了，
My father wasn't able for it anymore
你走了，一直没走
and you were gone and stayed gone.
仅此而已 没有其他的选择
That was that. No other option.
不想和别人合作
Didn't want to work it with anyone else.
上帝啊，这太不真实了
Jesus Christ  it's unreal.
地面有些地方有点软
Ground's a bit soft in parts.
你得换一些支架
You'll have to replace some of your trestles.
为你的牡蛎和包装袋找一个供应商
Find a supplier for your oysters and bags.
那就从种子或半生的种子开始吧
Start with seeds or half-growns  then.
至少在它们成熟前一年，就能盈利
Be a year at least before they mature  turn profit.
你得另找收入
You'll have to find another income.
但你自己也知道
But you know that yourself.
这不是你做不到的，布莱恩 是吗?
That's nothing you can't manage  though  Brian. Is it?
不是一个麻烦 操的缘故
Not a bother. For fuck's sake.
哦 对不起 艾琳 忘记打卡了
Oh  sorry  Aileen. Forgot to clock out.
-给我一分钟 -不 爱
-Just give me a minute. -No rush  love.
漂亮的牡蛎 谢谢你 佛朗斯
Fine looking oysters. Thanks  Francie.
如果他们抓到我们，你就疯了
Be some craic if they caught us.
别跟我这么说
Oh  don't say that to me.
你快点吧 来吧
Hurry up will you. Come on.
我在等你，妈妈
I'm waiting on you  Mom.
-晚饭见，好吗?-走吧，走吧
-See you for dinner  yeah? -Go on  aye  go away.
是安全的
Be safe.
玫瑰!
Hup!
谢谢你 伙计
Thank you  guys.
嗨，孩子，最近怎么样?
Hi  boy  how're things?
你就在那里
There you are.
来，拿点这个 继续
Here  take some of this. Go on.
来吧 给我们唱首歌吧
C'mon. Give us a song.
——去 -谢谢 妈妈
-Go on. -Thanks  Mom.
-给你，丹 好吧 好吧 我来帮你做一个
- There you go  Dan. Okay  all right. I'll do one for you.
♪我们走在黑暗中
♪ We go walking in the dark
♪我们晚上出去散步
♪ We go walking out at night
♪不是恋人走的路
♪ And it's not as lovers go
♪两个两个，来来回回，
♪ Two by two  to and fro
♪但是它是一个一个的
♪ But it's one by one
♪黑暗中一个一个的
♪ One by one in the dark
♪我们晚上出去散步
♪ We go walking out at night
澳大利亚怎么样?
What about Australia?
♪当我们漫步 穿过小草
♪ As we wander through the grass
你最喜欢那里的什么地方?嗯
-What was your favorite place down there? -Hmm.
♪我们可以听到彼此擦肩而过
♪ We can hear each other pass
你会惊讶于我对它的无知，爱玲
You'd be surprised how little I saw of it  Aileen.
如果我知道你在哪儿，我早就去看你了
If I'd known where you were  I'd have gone and visited you.
♪我们晚上出去散步
♪ We go walking out at night
那当然很好，但是……
That would have been nice all right  but...
你没错过什么
you didn't miss much.
♪草又黑又高
♪ Grass so dark and tall
再说了，回到这里是世界上最好的事情…
Besides  it's the best thing in the world being back here...
和你在一起
with you.
♪月亮落了
♪ And the moon is down
♪我们晚上出去散步
♪ We go walking out at night
♪如果我握着你的手
♪ If I held your hand in mine
♪我可以发光，我可以发光
♪ I could shine  I could shine
♪就像清晨的太阳
♪ Like the morning sun
♪像太阳♪
♪ Like the sun ♪
-你要去哪儿?-丹，我能再来一杯吗?
- Where you off to? - Could I get another  Dan?
-我要去抽支烟 -不 不 不 你哪也不能去
-I'm going for a smoke. -No  no  no. You're not going anywhere.
-我们得回家了 -不 我不想回家
-We've gotta go home. -No. I don't want to go home.
我不在乎 -我还不想回家
-I don't care. -I don't want to go home yet.
玛丽 是吧?
Mary  huh?
——没有 - - - - - -来吧
- No. - Come on.
我跟你说了，计数很低
I'm telling you the count is low.
数一遍
Count them again.
我数了两遍 袋子不够了
I counted them twice. There aren't enough bags.
你是在教我怎么工作吗，弗朗西?
You telling me how to do my job  Francie?
有人想骗我
Someone's trying to cheat me.
难道要从你的工资里扣吗?
Is it going to come out of your fucking wages?
听着，我只给你你要的
Listen  I'm only giving you what you asked for.
哦 等一等 你是说这和我有关!
Oh  hold on. You're saying it has to do with me!
-现在是我的错了，是吗?-嘿，嘿，发生什么事了，伙计们?
-It's my fault now  is it? -Hey  hey  what's the story here  lads?
这个小贱人想骗我
This little bitch is trying to cheat me.
滚蛋 佛朗斯
Fuck off  Francie.
那里的包太少了
There isn't near enough bags there.
我剩下的半成年人呢?
Where's the rest of my fuckin' half-growns?
我相信他们都在那里 你填对了，是吗?
I'm sure they're all there. You filled them right  didn't you?
真不敢想象我怎么就不能
Can't imagine how I couldn't have.
我用和上次一样的方法分的，就像
I split them the exact same way as I did last time  like.
因为你是个白痴，这就是原因 丹尼斯在这里吗?
Cause you're a moron  that's why. Is Dennis here?
我还没见过他，没有
I haven't seen him yet  no.
这是很容易犯的错误，姑娘 快走吧
It's an easy mistake to make  girl. Go on away quick.
里面太疯狂了，不是吗?
It's crazy inside there  isn't it?
真遗憾那天晚上你和弗朗西比我们早回家了
Shame you and Francie had to go home early on us the other night.
我一直在寻求空间，他对此很不高兴
I've been taking space  and he's not been happy about it.
昨晚之后，我就把他的手擦干了
Wiped my hands of him after the last night.
但我却在这里痛哭流涕，好像是他伤了我的心
But here I am crying my eyes out as if he's the one who broke my heart.
不过，我也没办法
Can't help it  though.
慢慢来
Take your time with it.
我已经回我父母家好几晚了
I've been back in my parents' house a couple of nights.
时间很快就会把这一切都看清楚
Time puts it all into perspective very quickly.
他说话很粗暴
He was brutal with his words.
尽管如此，他还是和其他人一样
Still  though  he's just like anyone else really.
我们都是上帝在黑暗中的造物
We're all God's creatures in the dark.
这是四个鲑鱼
That's four salmon.
给你200
Two hundred to you.
好男人
Good man.
——谢谢 ——干杯
- Thanks. - Cheers.
工作怎么样，康?
How's work going  Con?
啊，我想是我发明的
Ah  coining it  I suppose.
这是从哪里来的?
Where's this come from?
你以为你是个硬汉，是吗?战斗系统
You think you're a hard man  do you? Fighting the system.
只挖人，好像你不懂似的
Poaching alone  as if you didn't know better.
这不是你以前没做过的事，康
It's nothing you didn't do back in the day  Con.
我从不在春潮时外出
I never went out on spring tides.
马克也是这么死的
Sure Mark died doing the same thing.
那不是你最终会发生的事，就是你会被抓
And that's either what will happen to you eventually  or you'll be caught.
都指向同一个目标，就像 愚蠢
All points to the same end  like. Stupidity.
天啊，放轻松，伙计
Jesus Christ  lighten up  mate.
她为你偷的包还不够吗?
The bags she stole for you weren't enough  no?
你诚实地吃了这些生蚝才坚持了多久?
You lasted all of about how long making an honest go of the oysters?
反正比我估计的要长 算你公平
Longer than I reckoned anyway. Fair play to you.
你一直告诉我什么能做什么不能做，
You keep telling me what I can and can't do
但我要维持帕迪的农场
but I'm keeping Paddy's farm going.
你父亲只是想说你不必冒这个险
Your father's only trying to say that you don't have to take such a risk.
谢谢你，妈妈
Thanks for that  Mom.
这是怎么回事，小伙子?
What's the story here  lad?
看看有没有我可以利用的东西
Checking if there isn't anything I can make use of.
天啊，事情就这么糟，是吗?
Christ  things are that bad  are they?
你就像只老鼠
You're like a rat.
大部分都是我的旧东西
Most of this is my old shite.
它早已没有任何用处了
It's long past being any use.
为自己投资一些新事物
Invest in a few new things for yourself.
还是给自己一个机会吧，孩子
Give yourself a chance anyway  boy.
告诉我们 什么…你明天做什么?
Tell us  what... what are you doing tomorrow?
嗯…
Uh...
我得说，涨潮后晚上再出发
head out in the evening after the tide  I'd say.
我猜你早上有空吧?
So  you're free in the morning  I take it?
我可以给你一份工作
Could have a job for you.
我是说，把这些都用了，我可以额外给你一点钱
I mean  use these away sure and I could pay you a bit extra on top.
这很艰难，不是吗?
It's tough  isn't it...
你一个人做吗?
doin' it by yourself?
这对一个人来说太过分了
It's too much  really  for one man.
这是你父亲学到的教训
It's the lesson your father learned.
这些很适合布莱恩，对吧?
These would fit Brian  would they?
玛丽，你还好吗?
Are you all right  Mary?
我一个人的时候总觉得听到马克的声音
I keep thinking I hear Mark when I'm here alone.
夜里的声音……
A sound at night...
可能是他在这里四处走动
and it might be him moving around the place.
奇怪的安慰
Strange comfort.
谢谢你 爱
Thanks  love.
布莱恩，你他妈的给我出来 你能快点吗?
Brian  come out the fuck. Can you hurry up?
哦
Oh.
得时刻注意潮水，伙计
Got to keep an eye on the tide  mate.
某个早晨，帕迪小子
Some morning out there  Paddy Boy.
一切都在变化，但是……
Everything supposedly shifts  but...
就像你，我和康一起工作的时候一样
it's exactly like it was when you  me  and Con were workin' it.
喝七喜瓶装的冷茶
Drinking cold tea out of a 7UP bottle
在晴朗的日子里，没有什么比这更好的了
on a clear day  there's nothing like it.
你在那儿吗?
Are you there at all?
狗屎…
Shit...
他妈的……
Fuck...
迪克 胡说 屁股
Dick  bollocks  arse.
你什么都没说?
You didn't say anything?
我什么都没告诉他，没有
I didn't tell him nothing  no.
九个月后，这家伙
Nine months later  this fella.
他是个黏人的小混蛋
He's a needy little fecker.
通常的家庭特征 男孩是男孩
The usual family traits. Boys being boys.
粘在妈妈的乳头上
Stuck to their mother's tit.
非常聪明的窥探
Lookin' very smart.
你想和我们一起下去吗?
Do you want to come down with us?
我该回家了
I should head home.
我们早上有一个早班
We've an early one in the morning.
我要去乡下住几天
Heading up the country for a few days.
让这个小个子知道，世界上还有更多的东西
Show the small man there's more to the world.
来吧 我们去炫耀你吧
Come on. Let's go show you off.
哦
Oh.
我…我不知道
I... I don't know.
圣诞节的跳投 -圣诞套头衫，就是这件
-Christmas jumper. -Christmas jumper  that's the one.
好吧 嗯……
Okay  um...
你可以去世界上任何地方
you could go anywhere in the world.
没有条件 你会去哪里?
No conditions. Where would you go?
你知道吗?
Do you know what...
我宁愿只是…时光倒流……
I'd rather just... reel the years back in...
让你和你父亲坐下来让你们表现得像个成年人
and sit you and your father down and make ye act like adults.
想象你们相处得很好，住在同一个屋檐下
It's nice imagining you getting along  living under the one roof.
但我为你现在的样子感到骄傲
But I'm proud the way you are now  though.
就好像作品本身就是它的开始和结束
It's as if the work itself was the beginning and the end of it.
嘿 丹
Hey  Dan.
——嘿 莎拉 -能给我来杯威士忌吗?
- Hey  Sarah. - Can I get a whiskey  please?
当然可以 是的
You can  of course. Yeah.
你想再喝一杯吗?
Did you want another drink?
不 不 呆在那里 我去拿，好吧
No. No  stay there. I'll get it  all right.
我给你拿这个
Let me get you this.
哦 你是大 谢谢 虽然
Oh  you're grand. Thanks  though.
你晚上出去了吗?
You out for the night?
看完这个我们就知道了
We'll see now after this one.
嗯
Mmm-hmm.
说实话，我真不敢相信你还在这
I can't believe you're still here  to be honest.
我以为你早就抛弃这里了
I thought you would have long abandoned this place.
我不知道你为什么会这么想
I don't know why you'd think that.
我需要的一切都在这里
Everything I ever needed was here.
不用自己去找
Didn't have to go looking for it.
嗯
Hmm.
像什么?
Like what?
不 我们年轻的时候经常一起疯，对吧?
Nah. We used to have a good craic together when we were younger  didn't we?
-美国吗?-Mmm-hmm
-Us? -Mmm-hmm.
那是很久以前的事了
It was so long ago.
如果我是你，我就不会纠结于此
I wouldn't get hung up on it if I were you.
你在喝什么?
What are you drinking?
去吧，给我个惊喜
Go on sure  surprise me.
我 嗯…两个一样的
I  um... two of the same again.
-她在喝威士忌，是吗?嗯
- Uh  she's having whiskey  is she? Mmm-hmm.
那就这样吧
There you go.
有……
There's...
退潮时间是什么时候?
What time is low tide due?
继续说，好吗?
Go on  will you?
好的 晚上 宠物
All right. Night  pet.
晚安，各位
Good night.
哪天晚上我可以借你的上衣穿，艾琳
I might borrow that top off you one of the nights  Aileen.
明天见，姑娘
I'll see you tomorrow  girl.
对不起 小伙子
Sorry  lads.
——早上好 ——早上好
- Good morning. - Good morning.
你昨晚出去了吗?
Were you out last night?
不 不 我不是 是你吗?
No  no. I was not. Were you out?
晚安，是吗?
Good night so  was it?
玛丽 你看
Mary  look.
的文采 停止传送带上 艾琳
-Look at that. -Stop the belt. Aileen.
真菌 狗屎
-Fungus. -Shit.
我们也有真菌
We've got fungus  too.
让我看看!
Let me see that!
检查一下剩下的存货
Check the rest of the stock.
把这些扔了
Throw these ones out.
操的缘故!一场灾难
Fuck's sake! What a disaster.
耶稣!
Jesus!
莎拉?——不要再碰我
-Sarah? -Don't touch me.
特此警告
You are hereby warned
停止养殖所有生蚝
to cease cultivation of all oyster holdings
直到进一步通知
until further notice
如果被发现违反暂停，可被吊销执照
punishable by loss of license if caught in breach of the moratorium.
你今天收获的所有牡蛎都必须销毁
Any oysters you harvested today must be destroyed.
你有工作给我吗?
Do you have any work for me?
不，我这段时间都不需要你了，不
No  I'm not gonna need you again for a while  no.
像其他人一样低头，你就会没事的
Keep your head down like the rest of 'em  you'll be grand.
我会收回你欠我的，所以
I'll take what you owe me  so.
好了，伙计们，把他们都扔出去 是的
All right  lads  let's throw them all out. Yeah.
我们现在该怎么办，比如?哦
What are we supposed to do now  like? Oh.
同样的事情也发生过，大概在七八年前，对吧?
Same thing happened  about seven or eight years ago  didn't it?
几乎摧毁了牡蛎养殖户
Nearly destroyed the oyster farmers.
一想到他们在家无所事事 对任何人都没有好处
The idea of them at home doing nothing. No good for anyone.
她的情况似乎越来越糟了，不是吗?
It seems to be gotten worse and worse for her  doesn't it?
可怜的cratur
Poor cratur.
她不是故意要咬你的
She didn't mean to bite at you.
如果弗朗西做了什么，她应该说出来
If Francie's done something  she needs to speak up about it.
——嘿 爱 -你好
- Hey  love. - Hiya.
你忙吗?
Are you busy?
不是时候，不是 我只是在装修房子
Not a great time  no. I'm just doing a few jobs on the house.
妈妈说他们几天没在工厂看到你了
Mom says they haven't seen you in the factory in a few days.
你终于闻到这味道了，是吗?
The smell's finally getting to you  is it?
不
No.
之后呢，姑娘?
What's after happening  girl?
我在这里，你知道的
I'm here  you know.
如果你需要什么 是吗?
If you need anything. Yeah?
是的
Yeah.
我不打扰你了
I'll let you get back to it.
谢谢
Thanks.
喂?
Hello?
艾琳
Aileen.
艾琳 近况如何?你现在可以跟我走了
Aileen. How are things? Hey  you might follow me through here now.
我们现在才进来，你看
We're just in here now  look.
大会进行得怎么样了?
How's Con gettin' on?
迈克 布莱恩在哪儿吗?
Where's Brian  Mike?
抱歉把你大老远拉过来
Sorry to drag you all the way into town.
你一定很高兴布莱恩回到家里和你在一起
You must be delighted to have Brian back in the house with you.
当然，你自己也知道
Sure  you know yourself.
你认为吗?
Do you reckon?
天知道如果我的女儿们搬回来住，
God knows if my girls moved back into the house
我们会把对方撕成碎片
we'd be tearing strips off each other.
他去了澳大利亚，是吗?
Australia he was  was it?
澳大利亚 是的
Australia  yeah.
不都是这样吗?伤了他母亲的心
Isn't that always the way? Breaking his mother's heart.
完全正确
Exactly.
听着，已经有人索赔了
Look  there's been a claim made
关于几周前村里发生的一起袭击案
about an assault in the village a couple of weeks back
被丹·内尔的酒吧里的一个年轻女人所杀
by a young woman who was in Dan Nell's pub
在4月18日晚上
on the night of the 18th of April.
布莱恩说那晚他和你在家里
Brian says he was at home with you that night.
是这样吗?
Is that right?
他是 是的
He was  yeah.
-他在任何阶段都没有出去过…-不 不
-He didn't go out or anything at any stage... -No. No.
你会在法庭上再说一遍吗?
And you'd say that again in court?
我会的 是的
I would. Yeah.
好的 听着，我知道，布莱恩是个勤奋的人
All right. Look  I know  well  Brian's a hard-workin' fella.
就是这样吗？
Is that it?
我现在就去叫他 一分钟
I'll give him a shout for you there now. One minute.
有点过分了，迈克，不是吗，
It's a bit much  Mike  isn't it
大半夜的把我拖出来就为了问一个简单的问题?
to drag me out in the middle of the night just to ask a simple question?
我们得让人看到我们在做本职工作，艾琳
We've to be seen to be doing our job  Aileen.
你还好吗?
Are you all right?
嗯 我得去喝几杯
Huh. Need to go for a few pints.
我的货车在回来的路上 我们可能会捡起来
My van is on the way back. We might pick it up.
外面还有其他人吗，你记得吗?
Was there anyone else out  do you remember?
我不能告诉你
I couldn't tell you.
我离开你之后发生了什么?
What happened after I left you?
我们喝了几杯
We had a few drinks.
没有我们以前做过的事
Nothing we didn't do back in the day.
这是什么意思?
What does that mean?
耶稣基督……
Jesus Christ...
我是不是该他妈的回澳大利亚去?
Am I better off going back to fucking Australia?
就是这样吗？被扯进这破事里
Is that it? Getting dragged into this shit.
你哪也不能去，好吗?
You're not going anywhere  all right?
你听到了吗?
Do you hear me?
谢谢 妈妈
Thanks  Mom.
重点是，禁令不会持续太久
The moratorium won't last  is the point.
再过几周，水就会冷却，
In a couple of weeks  the water will cool
一切都将神奇地重置
all will magically reset.
牡蛎养殖户又来了，好像什么都没发生过
Oyster farmers coining it again  like nothing ever happened.
这就是时间的作用
That's what time does.
教训在年轻人身上浪费了
Lesson wasted on the young.
艾琳?艾琳
Aileen? Aileen.
下周我能加班吗?
Are there any extra hours I can pick up next week?
你可以替莎拉的班
You might cover Sarah's shifts.
你没有她的消息吗?
You haven't heard from her?
我有 是的
I have. Yeah.
我们被守卫盯上了
We've had Guards into us.
Yera 不…
Yera  no...
他们只是想和顾客交谈
they were just looking to talk to customers
他们几个星期前来过
who were in a few weeks back.
那是一个宁静的夜晚……
It was a quiet night...
我就是这么告诉他们的
That's what I told them.
现在更符合他们的口味了
It'd be more in their line now
看着外国拖网渔船蹂躏我们的海洋，是吧?
to be looking into foreign trawlers raping our oceans  huh?
他们无能为力，反正他们会这么告诉你的
Their hands are tied  that's what they'll tell you anyway.
为什么耶稣不是出生在澳大利亚?
Why wasn't Jesus born in Australia?
Oye
Oye.
啊，因为他…
Ah  'cause he was...
晚上 小伙子
Night  lads.
——好的 -是的
- All right. - Yeah.
你明天还来吗，姑娘?
Are you in with us tomorrow again  girl?
我 是的 谢谢
I am  yeah. Thanks.
-晚安 ——夜
- Night to you. - Night.
的夜晚
Night.
因为没有智者……
Because there was no wise men...
不是处女
No virgins either.
-好的 嗯
-All right. -Hmm.
好男人
Good man.
来吧……
Come on...
——夜 -晚安 的夜晚
- Night. - Night to you. Night.
布莱恩在吗?
Is Brian in?
他会被起诉的
A charge is gonna be brought against him.
他需要在本周的今天到地方法院出庭，
He needs to present himself in front of the district court today week
初审将在法官面前进行
and an initial remand will be made in front of a judge.
看在上帝的份上，迈克
For fuck sake  Mike.
听着，确保他在那，好吗?
Look  just make sure he's there  will you?
你告诉他们你那晚没出去
You told them you weren't out that night.
但我们都知道那是个谎言
But we both know that's a lie  though.
你知道些什么，艾琳?
What do you know about it  Erin?
弗朗西虐待了她多少年，
There's Francie mistreating her for how many years
没人在意
and nobody thinks anything of it.
突然间所有人都认为布莱恩是问题所在
And suddenly everyone reckons that Brian's the problem.
他这辈子都没碰过女人
Who never put a hand on a woman in his life.
你自己也说莎拉出事后出事了
You said yourself something was after happening to Sarah.
也许是弗朗西
Maybe it was Francie  yeah.
但你不想听听她的说法吗?
But you don't want to hear her side?
你还好吗?
Are you all right?
莎拉今天又不在家?
Sarah's not in again today?
你什么时候回来?
What time will you be back?
我不知道
I don't know.
如果他回来受审怎么办?
What happens if he's returned for trial?
♪在清醒和睡觉的时候
♪ At waking time and sleeping
♪那就是我渴望去的地方
♪ It's there I'd long to be
♪要再走一遍
♪ To walk again
♪那些亲切的街道
♪ Those kindly streets
♪我出生的地方
♪ The place where I was born
来吧
Come on.
它是如何结束的?
How does it finish?
嗯?
Hmm?
♬与男孩 from Barr na Sraide
♪ With the boys from Barr na Sraide
追捕的♪
♪ Who hunted
♪对于鹪鹩…♪我> < /
♪ For the wren... ♪
你没有问题，帕迪，伙计
There's nothing wrong with you  Paddy  mate.
嗯
Hmm.
你只是在和我们其他人开玩笑
You're only playing a trick on the rest of us.
你们还有其他歌曲吗?
What other songs do you have?
一段McAlpines?嗯?
A verse of McAlpines? Hmm?
一场The Wild Rover也许?
A blast of The Wild Rover maybe?
好男人
Good man.
嗯
Hm.
投诉人等了一个星期才提出报告
The complainant waited a week before making her report
并声称在袭击发生当晚她被跟踪到了当地码头
and claims she was followed down to the local pier on the night of the assault
被告随后在那里强奸了她
and that the defendant subsequently raped her down there.
被告的母亲为他提供了不在场证明，法官
The defendant's mother has provided him with an alibi  Judge.
她重申了她和被告当时在房子里的证词
And she reaffirms the statement that she and the defendant were in the house
在事发当晚的几个小时里，
during the hours of the night in question
被告和她一起待在房子里
that the defendant remained in the house with her
在被侵犯的几小时内?
during the hours of the claimed assault?
是的，法官阁下 是的
I do  Your Honor. Yes.
嗯
Hmm.
这是一个严重的指控
This is a serious accusation.
这也是被告第一次出庭
It's also the first time the defendant has been before the court.
现在我的观点是没有足够的…
Now it's my opinion that there's not enough...
在公诉证据簿上
in the Book of Evidence for the State to prosecute.
有关控罪将发还民进党作进一步指示
Charges will be remanded back to the DPP for further instructions.
我还认为，这项指控不应提交法庭
I also believe that this charge should not have been brought before the court.
被告可以离开了
Uh  the defendant is free to leave.
接下来是什么?
What's next?
文件15日法官
File 15  Judge.
醉酒和无序
Drunk and disorderly.
艾琳 过来一下，好吗?
Aileen. Come here a minute  will you?
她最近出勤情况如何?
What's her attendance lately?
16个班中有14个没来
Fourteen of 16 shifts missed.
我可以把日子补上 拜托
I can make the days up. Please.
还有谁在同一时间翘了班吗?
Has anyone else missed a shift in the same time?
你应该让我们知道的至少，打电话请病假
You could have let us know at least  you know  called in sick.
但我必须让你走，姑娘
But I have to let you go  girl.
你是对的 丹尼斯
You're right  Dennis.
我应该让你知道我发生了什么
I should've let you know what's been happening with me.
这是个错误，对吧?
That was the mistake  yeah?
不过这对你来说很方便，不是吗?
It's all very convenient for you  though  isn't it?
弗朗西的生蚝袋和其他东西，
Between Francie's oyster bags and everything else
每个人都他妈的闭着眼睛
everyone's got their fucking eyes closed.
等等，等一下
Wait  hang on a second.
莎拉?
Sarah?
那牡蛎袋呢，莎拉?
What about the oyster bags  Sarah?
来吧，伙计们，集中注意力，回到工作上
Come on lads  focus  back on the work.
她说弗兰西的牡蛎是什么意思，艾琳?
What does she mean about Francie's oysters  Aileen?
回家了
Go home.
-什么?-回家吧
-What? -Go home for the day.
奥斯卡 爱
Oscar  love.
你不能瞒着我就把他从日托所带走
You can't just take him out of daycare without telling me.
他不是你儿子
He's not your son.
我不想让你再照顾他了
I don't want you looking after him anymore.
他妈的 艾琳 她还是他的祖母
Fuck's sake  Erin. She's still his grandmother.
如果你真的和她坐在一起
If you'd actually sit with her
你不可能这么轻易地否认发生了什么，艾琳
you wouldn't be able to deny what happened so easily  Aileen.
-对她宽容点 ——没有
- Go easy on her. - No.
妈的，她得听我说
For fuck's sake  she needs to hear it.
我会和她谈谈的
I'll talk to her.
你对他一定要小心
You have to be careful with him.
莎拉在这里的时候，这里是艾琳的房间
And all the time that Sarah was in here  when it was Erin's room.
我以前常拿你们俩跟她妈妈开玩笑，
I used to joke with her mother about the two of you
我们会成为亲家
that we'd be in-laws.
她在牡蛎袋的事上撒谎了吗，艾琳?
Was she lying about the oyster bags  Aileen?
我得先让你接电话直到我弄清楚到底是怎么回事
I'm gonna have to put you on the line until I figure out what the story is.
禁令的解除
Moratorium's been lifted.
疯狂的几个星期
Be a mad few weeks.
可能得多雇几个人手了
Might have to hire a few more hands.
于是这个故事传开了，
So the story went round
几个月来，人们都以为他妻子死了
and for months  people thought the wife died
因为她为了救火鸡掉进了井里
'cause she'd fallen down the well tryin' to save the turkey.
那个守卫是个聪明的家伙
It was some clever prick  the guard.
下周日弥撒后你们能过来就太好了
It'd be great to have you all over next Sunday after mass.
让你休息一下吧
Give you a rest for once.
让你休息一下
Be a break for you.
好像他一直在等这个问题
As if he'd been waiting for that question the entire time.
我要做苹果酥
I'll do my apple crumble.
“因为她是个讨厌的婊子，这就是原因 ”
"Because she was an annoying bitch  that's why."
请来两杯杜松子酒和一杯奎宁水
Two gins and a tonic  please?
不是今晚 不是
Not tonight  no.
什么?
What?
我们保留拒绝服务的权利，亲爱的
We retain the right to refuse service here  love.
帮你自己一个忙，安静地走吧
Do yourself a favor and go quietly.
嗯?
Hmm?
你们都去死吧
You can all go to fuckin' hell.
呆在原地别动，小伙子
You stay where you are now  lad.
抓住他，伙计们
Hold on to him there  boys.
你现在不去跟踪她吗?
Don't you go following her now  eh?
我讨厌这些传统的东西
I hate these traditional things.
只是为了丢脸而丢脸
Showing face just for the sake of it.
我可能懒得去了
I might not bother going.
做你想做的
Do what you want.
♬我创造了夜晚的星星
♪ I who made the stars of night
♪我会让 他们的黑暗明亮
♪ I will make their darkness bright
♪谁来为他们承担 我的光?
♪ Who will bear my light to them?
♬我该派谁去呢?
♪ Whom shall I send?
♪我在这里，主
♪ Here I am  Lord
♬是我吗，主?
♪ Is it I  Lord?
♪我听说过
♪ I have heard
♪你在夜里打电话
♪ You calling in the night
♪我要走了，上帝
♪ I will go  Lord
♪如果你引导我
♪ If you lead me
♪我会紧握
♪ I will hold
♪你的人在我心里
♪ Your people in my heart
♪我在这里，主
♪ Here I am  Lord
♬是我吗，主?
♪ Is it I  Lord?
♪我听说过
♪ I have heard
♪你在夜里打电话
♪ You calling in the night
♪我要走了，上帝
♪ I will go  Lord
♪如果你引导我
♪ If you lead me
♪我会坚持…♪我> < /
♪ I will hold... ♪
今天是晚潮
It's a late tide today.
艾琳
Aileen.
艾琳，你能过来一下吗?
Aileen  would you come in here?
我 呃…
I'll  uh...
…主与你同在  你在妇女中是有福的，
...Lord is with thee. Blessed art thou amongst women
和祝福的果实 你的子宫耶稣
and blessed is the fruit of thy womb Jesus.
圣母玛利亚，
Holy Mary  mother of God
现在和我们死的时候为我们罪人祈祷 阿们
pray for us sinners now and at the hour of our death. Amen.
万福玛利亚，充满圣宠，主与你同在
Hail Mary  full of grace  the Lord is with thee.
你在妇女中是有福的，你所怀的子耶稣也是有福的
Blessed art thou amongst women  and blessed is the fruit of thy womb Jesus.
圣母玛利亚，
Holy Mary  mother of God
现在和我们死的时候为我们罪人祈祷 阿们
pray for us sinners now and at the hour of our death. Amen.
万福玛利亚，充满圣宠，主与你同在
Hail Mary  full of grace  the Lord is with thee.
你在妇女中是有福的，你所怀的子耶稣也是有福的
Blessed art thou amongst women  and blessed is the fruit of thy womb Jesus.
圣母玛利亚，
Holy Mary  mother of God
现在和我们死的时候为我们罪人祈祷 阿们
pray for us sinners now and at the hour of our death. Amen.
万福玛利亚，充满圣宠，主与你同在
Hail Mary  full of grace  the Lord is with thee.
你在妇女中是有福的，你所怀的子耶稣也是有福的
Blessed art thou amongst women  and blessed is the fruit of thy womb Jesus.
圣母玛利亚，
Holy Mary  mother of God
现在和我们死的时候为我们罪人祈祷 阿们
pray for us sinners now and at the hour of our death. Amen.
万福玛利亚，充满圣宠，主与你同在
Hail Mary  full of grace  the Lord is with thee.
你在妇女中是有福的，你所怀的子耶稣也是有福的
Blessed art thou amongst women  and blessed is the fruit of thy womb Jesus.
圣母玛利亚，
Holy Mary  mother of God
现在和我们死的时候为我们罪人祈祷 阿们
pray for us sinners now and at the hour of our death. Amen.
万福玛利亚，充满圣宠，主与你同在……
Hail Mary  full of grace  the Lord is with thee...
-请节哀顺变 ——谢谢
- Sorry for your loss. - Thank you.
谢谢你！
Thank you.
请节哀顺变
I'm so sorry for your loss.
谢谢你！
Thank you.
请节哀顺变
I'm so sorry for your loss.
-请节哀顺变 ——谢谢
- I'm sorry for your loss. - Thanks.
- Sorry for your loss. - Thank you.
对你的损失我很遗憾，康
I'm sorry for your loss  Con.
谢谢你 莎拉
Thanks  Sarah.
——莎拉!-他妈的别碰她
- Sarah! - Don't fuckin' touch her.
对你的损失表示哀悼，布莱恩 ——谢谢
Condolences for your loss  Brian. - Thanks.
好像整个世界都颠倒了
Seems like the whole world has turned upside down.
这是有史以来最操蛋的事，妈妈
It's just as fucked as it's ever been  Mom.
如果你是那个转弯的人，情况可能会不一样 但是…
It might look different if you're the one turning. But...
什么都没有改变
nothing's changed.
相信我
Trust me.
不过你那样插手是对的
You were right stepping in like that  though.
我们要回家了
We're going to head home.
得到一些休息
Get some rest.
你也应该这么做
You should  too.
嗯?
Huh?
你想要什么?
What do you want?
嗯，我想是威士忌
Um  whiskey  I guess.
你想要威士忌吗?-是的
-You want whiskey? -Yeah.
来，请来两杯威士忌
Here  two whiskeys  please.
两种威士忌 嗯?
Two whiskeys  huh?
-是的 -你看起来很好
- Yeah. - You look great.
——谢谢 -你们好吗，小伙子们?
- Thanks. - How're ye  lads?
-你喜欢威士忌，是吗?嗯
-Do you like whiskey  you do? -Hmm.
噢 是吗?
Oh  yeah?
-这是给你的 -谢谢
-That one's for you. -Thanks.
布莱恩?
Brian?
-艾琳，你认识艾玛，是吗?-你好
-Aileen  you know Emma  you do? -Hi.
你最好回家去，姑娘 他对你来说有点老了
You're better off going home  girl. He's a bit old for you.
你在做什么?
What are you doing?
你怎么会觉得这样合适呢?
In what world did you ever think that this would be appropriate?
你在说什么?
What're you talking about?
妈的，你以为我是谁啊，妈?
For fuck's sake  who do you think I am at all  Mom?
嘿 嘿 别把你的手放在你妈妈身上
Hey  hey. Don't put your hands on your mother.
反对 …反对!-你真他妈丢人
-Con  what the... Con! -You're a fucking disgrace.
离开我!
Get off me!
下车!
Get off!
如果你是来喊的，就别费事了 我要出去
If you're here to shout  don't fuckin' bother. I'm going out.
想象一下一年后这里会是什么样子?
Imagine what it'll be like out here in a year?
这是我们周围的投资，就像
This is the investment round us  like.
你对发生的事没有感觉吗，没有吗?
Do you not feel anything about what's happened  no?
关于莎拉…
About Sarah...
你对她做的事?
about what you did to her?
别那样看着我，好吗?
Don't look at me like that  will you?
这对你来说毫无意义吗?
Does it mean absolutely nothing to you?
你没有心或感觉了吗?
Is there no heart or feeling in you?
耶稣基督!
Jesus Christ!
你对我的印象太不可思议了，艾琳
You have this impossible image of me  Aileen.
我们继续吧，好吗?
Let's just move forward  all right?
我要你滚出我们的生活
I want you out of our lives.
妈妈!
Mom!
莎拉，亲爱的，我能进来吗?
Sarah  love  can I step in?
我惭愧 女孩 坐在你的家里
I'm ashamed  girl. Sitting in your house.
很抱歉打扰你，我…
I'm sorry to be bothering you  I...
我不知道我为什么要这么做 我…
I don't know why I had to. I...
我不会解释的
I'm not explaining myself.
你不该走的
You shouldn't be leaving.
过去几周的风…
The wind the past few weeks...
这些房子太他妈糟糕了
These houses are so fuckin' bad for it.
我想玛丽听到的就是这个
I suppose that's what Mary was hearing.
所有房间都能听到马克的声音
Sound of Mark in all the rooms.
只是风吹过
Just the wind getting through.
我以前晚上听我妈说话的方式，
The way I used to listen to my mother at nights
在爸爸生气的时候抱着他上床
carrying Dad down to bed when he'd be pissed.
听到她那晚之后四处走动，
Hearing her moving around the rest of the night then
独自哭泣
crying away to herself.
我只是躺在自己的房间里
Me just lying there in my own room.
20年前，我还能听到他们的回音
Twenty years ago  and I can still hear their echo.
我想这附近的每栋房子都有同样的鬼魂
I suppose every house around here has the same ghosts.
妈妈很自豪能把这所房子留给我
Mom was so proud of the fact that she was able to leave me this house.
我会在她死后住在这里
I'd live here after she did
等等……直到潮水把它冲走
and so on... until the tide takes it.
以前我总是在你家醒来，艾琳…
All the times I used to wake up in your house  Aileen...
布莱恩躺在我旁边的床上
Brian in the bed beside me.
同样的风让我每晚睡不着觉
That same wind keeping me awake every night.
是不是他的声音一直萦绕在我心头……
Is it the sound of him that's haunting me...
和其他鬼魂一起吗?
with all these other ghosts?
过去的雷声袭来
The thunder of pasts getting in.
因为突然之间，我…
Because all of a sudden  I...
我不知道我在哪里
I don't know where I am.
好像这房子和它所有的历史都不是我的
As if this house and all its history wasn't mine.